MOHAMED ASHAR

SENIOR UI DEVELOPER

GET IN TOUCH

Email: myselfmohamedashar@gmail.com
Contact Number: +919747408804

LANGUAGES

English / Hindi / Tamil / Malayalam

INTERESTS

Football / Music / Travel

PROFILE

Technical Lead Cum Senior UI Developer with over 10+ years of experience in the integral sectors of structuring, developing and executing interactive web applications. Extensive experience in producing client-side scripting and a respectable root in server-side technologies. Expertise administered to the promising analysis, problem-solving mastery, and sharp adaption of changes in the working domain.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS3.

Client-Side Technologies

Angular, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, SASS, LESS.

Application Libraries

Angular JS, JQuery.

UI Component Libraries

Bootstrap, Material Design.

Development Tools

Visual Studio, VS Code, Chrome, Sublime.

Others

Karma, Jasmine, Jest, GIT, JIRA, NPM, Webpack, Adobe Photoshop.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- <> Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt Ltd, Chennai India.
 Role: Lead Consultant-Technology (July 2022 till date).
- <> Addant Systems, Technopark Trivandrum India.

 Role: UI Lead cum Senior UI Developer (May 2016 June 2022).
- <> Aptara Learning Pvt Ltd, Technopark Trivandrum India.
 Role: Senior UI Developer (December 2014 to May 2016).
- <> Verbat Technologies Pvt Ltd, Trivandrum India.
 Role: Senior UI Developer (December 2012 to July 2014).
- <> Sod Technologies Pvt Ltd, Cochin India.
 Role: Ul Developer (May 2012 to December 2012).

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- <> Bachelor of Computer Applications
 Annamalai University, Tamilnadu, India.
- <> Diploma in Multimedia

 Arena Animation, Kerala, India.

PROJECTS

Project: CONTACT 360

Description: Contact 360 is a US based CITI bank web application. This application using for monitoring and customizing client

coverage data.

Responsibilities: Technical Lead, UI Development, Requirement Analysis, Module Development, Task Discussions, Design Documents,

Code review, Bug fixes.

Technologies: Angular 14, Jest (UT Coverage), HTML5, SASS.

Project: CRM DASHBOARD TTS

Description: CRM Dashboard TTS is a US based CITI bank web application. This application is handling entire bank related widgets like

Account Summary, Currency Details, PF Coverage Details etc.

Responsibilities: Technical Lead, UI Development, Requirement Analysis, Module Development, Task Discussions, Design Documents,

Code review, Bug fixes.

Technologies: Angular 14, Jest (UT Coverage), HTML5, SASS.

Project: WLCR (WHOLE SELL CREDIT REVIEWS)

Description: WLCR is a US based CITI bank web application. This application for customizing loan applications. Modules are

RAC Assessment and Policy Exceptions.

Responsibilities: Technical Lead, UI Development, Requirement Analysis, Module Development, Task Discussions, Design Documents,

Code review, Bug fixes.

Technologies: Angular 14, Jest (UT Coverage), Cypress, HTML5, SASS.

Project: HELIOS

Description: Helios is angular schematics application. It helps to create an application using CLI commands.

Responsibilities: Technical Lead, UI development, Requirement analysis, Module development, Task discussions,

Design documents, Code review, Bug fixes.

Technologies: Angular 14, HTML5, SASS.

Project: CERTUS

Description: Certus is a UK based casino web application. This application gives the details about casino and its players.

Administrator can do various settings through this application.

Responsibilities: UI development, Requirement analysis, Module development, Task discussions, Design documents, Code review, Bug fixes.

Technologies: Angular 9, HTML5, Bootstrap, Jasmin.

Project: MENTIS

Description: Mentis is Malaysian based web application. This application is related to car booking and car parking services.

Responsibilities: UI development, Requirement analysis, Module development, Task discussions, Design documents, Code review, Bug fixes.

Technologies: Angular 5, HTML5, Bootstrap, Jasmin.

Project: PAPA JOHN'S INTERNATIONAL

Description: PROHealth is an online platform where doctors can monitor the health reports of patients. Diagnosis performed by specialised

devices can be connected to this application. Patients can visit doctors through this application.

Responsibilities: UI development, Requirement analysis, Design documents, Code review, Bug fixes

Technologies: Angular 2, HTML5, Bootstrap.

Project: PROHEALTH

Description: PROHealth is an online platform where doctors can monitor the health reports of patients. Diagnosis performed by specialised

devices can be connected to this application. Patients can visit doctors through this application.

Responsibilities: UI development, Requirement analysis, Design documents, Code review, Bug fixes

Technologies: Angular JS, HTML5, Bootstrap.

Declaration